<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ivan Font (Posts about nginx)</title><link>http://ivanfont.com/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://ivanfont.com/categories/nginx.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 04:49:48 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Pac-Man Application Using Kubernetes Federation</title><link>http://ivanfont.com/posts/pac-man-application-using-kubernetes-federation/</link><dc:creator>Ivan Font</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pac-Man Microservices Architecture Game Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I discussed the next phase of the
&lt;a href="http://ivanfont.com/posts/pacman-nginx-app/"&gt;Pac-Man + NGINX + PHP + MongoDB Kubernetes reference application&lt;/a&gt;
was to deploy the application using a
&lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/user-guide/federation/"&gt;Kubernetes Federation&lt;/a&gt;.
This was accomplished and you can
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/k8s-example-apps/blob/master/pacman-nginx-app/docs/pacman-nginx-app-federated-cluster.md"&gt;read about the details here&lt;/a&gt;.
But in general, federation made it really easy to
manage multiple Kubernetes clusters through one pane of glass by deploying the Pac-Man Kubernetes
resources onto the clusters that are part of the federation. It automatically added the necessary
DNS entries for the services deployed to provide a load balanced application across all of the
clusters. This turned the Pac-Man microservices architecture game into a fully scalable
high-availability game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;New Features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;MongoDB Replica Set&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of moving to a federation required a data replication strategy so your application's data could
scale horizontally as well. This required setting up a
&lt;a href="https://docs.mongodb.com/manual/replication/"&gt;MongoDB Replica Set&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately, MongoDB requires
many operations to only be performed on the primary. For example, MongoDB allows reading from many
instances, but only the primary can receive writes. In addition, adding replica set members can only
be done on the primary. Unfortunately this, combined with the fact that federation at the time of
this writing does not yet support things like
&lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/abstractions/controllers/statefulsets/"&gt;StatefulSets&lt;/a&gt;,
involved a bit of manual intervention to bootstrap the MongoDB replica set than I would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Pac-Man Zone&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the application was deployed in the federation, I modified it to add a &lt;code&gt;Zone:&lt;/code&gt; field that would
retrieve the zone of the Pac-Man game instance you were connecting to via the load balanced DNS.
That is, the federated DNS was updated to resolve to the set of IP addresses of the Pac-Man
game service in each of the federated zones to provide load balancing. Multiple refreshes of
the game would continually update the zone you were connecting to and display that for you
above your score. Once you were done playing and saved your high score, the zone
information was also saved along with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Learnings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I was creating the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/kubernetes-cluster-federation/tree/v1.5.3"&gt;Kubernetes federation manually&lt;/a&gt;
but this became cumbersome and time consuming so I moved to use
&lt;a href="https://kubernetes.io/docs/admin/federation/kubefed/"&gt;kubefed&lt;/a&gt; which really helped speed up
the process of creating a federated cluster.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/k8s-example-apps/blob/master/pacman-nginx-app/docs/kubernetes-cluster-federation.md"&gt;Steps for doing that are captured here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, I learned about some limitations with MongoDB and not having StatefulSets that may pose
problems as the application evolves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'd like to see about performing coordinated migrations of the application as well as handling
failover. What would make those tests more interesting is having a larger volume of transactions
happening in the game, such as updating more data points on a regular interval defined in the game,
while performing those tests. In order to increase complexity in the game I've contemplated
migrating the backend to something more adept at handling that task. In any event, doing failover
tests may bump up against limitations of MongoDB and the lack of Statefulsets. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;GitHub Link&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read all about the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/k8s-example-apps/blob/master/pacman-nginx-app/docs/pacman-nginx-app-federated-cluster.md"&gt;details of how to set up the Pac-Man microservices architecture game here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>game</category><category>gce</category><category>google compute engine</category><category>kubernetes</category><category>mongodb</category><category>nginx</category><category>pacman</category><guid>http://ivanfont.com/posts/pac-man-application-using-kubernetes-federation/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 01:33:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pac-Man NGINX PHP MongoDB Application</title><link>http://ivanfont.com/posts/pacman-nginx-app/</link><dc:creator>Ivan Font</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Intro&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started working on a Kubernetes reference application for demonstration purposes. This reference application will continue to evolve
to also work with cloud federation capabilities in Kubernetes. I will provide updates as the application evolves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pac-Man Game Architecture Brief Overview&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Pac-Man&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Pac-Man game is a slightly modified version of the open source Pac-Man game written in HTML5 with Javascript. You can get the modified
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/pacman-canvas"&gt;Pac-Man game source code here&lt;/a&gt;. The modifications are particularly around the backend PHP API. The original
game used SQLite3 as the storage backend for reading and writing high scores. This change replaces SQLite3 with &lt;a href="https://www.mongodb.com/"&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt;
as the storage mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;NGINX + PHP FPM&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nginx.com/"&gt;NGINX&lt;/a&gt; is used as the web server to host the Pac-Man game application. It is configured with &lt;a href="https://php-fpm.org/"&gt;PHP FPM&lt;/a&gt; support for the backend PHP API.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;PHP&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PHP FPM is used for the PHP API to receive read and write requests from clients and perform database operations. The
&lt;a href="http://php.net/manual/en/set.mongodb.php"&gt;PHP MongoDB driver extension&lt;/a&gt; contains the minimal API for core driver functionality. In addition, the
&lt;a href="http://php.net/manual/en/mongodb.tutorial.library.php"&gt;PHP library for MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; provides the higher level APIs. Both are needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;MongoDB&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mongodb.com/"&gt;MongoDB&lt;/a&gt; is used as the backend database to store the Pac-Man game's high score user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a detailed overview of the Kubernetes reference application and how to set it up yourself, see the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/font/k8s-example-apps/tree/master/pacman-nginx-app"&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; in the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Have fun!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://ivanfont.com/images/pacman.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>game</category><category>gce</category><category>google compute engine</category><category>kubernetes</category><category>mongodb</category><category>nginx</category><category>pacman</category><guid>http://ivanfont.com/posts/pacman-nginx-app/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:35:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>